<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./taverna.png" type="Other" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
    <name>Taverna</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Execute Taverna workflow
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Execute a  <a href="http://www.taverna.org.uk/">Taverna</a> workflow. 
        <p>Note that the
        Taverna <a href="http://www.taverna.org.uk/download/command-line-tool/">Commandline</a> Tool 
        <tt>executeworkflow</tt> must be separately installed and made available on the operating system's PATH; 
        alternatively the full path to <tt>executeworkflow</tt> must be configured on each Taverna node.
        </p>
        <p>
        Taverna workflows can be found on the <a href="http://www.myexperiment.org/workflows?filter=TYPE_ID%28%222%22%29">myExperiment</a>
        website, or created using the <a href="http://www.taverna.org.uk/download/workbench/">Taverna Workbench</a>.        
        </p>
        <p>
        Most Taverna workflows will output multiple ports, each with a lists of values or list of lists of values.         
        This KNIME node has a single output port, where each Taverna output port corresponds to a single column.                      
        These lists are not necessarily of the same length, any the shorter columns will be padded with missing values.
        Required Taverna workflow inputs are selected from the table input to the node - 
        see the <b>View: Column names</b> for a list of ports of the configured workflow. 
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Taverna Workflow">File path or URL to Taverna workflow definition (.t2flow file)
        <p>
	        If using an URL from <a href="http://www.myexperiment.org/">myExperiment</a>, 
	        copy the <i>Run this Workflow in the Taverna Workbench</i> 
	        URL rather than the URL for the workflow page. 
        </p>
        
        </option>
        <option name="Timeout (seconds)">Maximum execution time in seconds, or 0 for no limit</option>
        <option name="executeworkflow binary">Path to installed Taverna CommandLine tool binary, 
        e.g. <tt>executeworkflow</tt> (from PATH) or <tt>/opt/taverna-commandline-core/executeworkflow</tt></option>

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="inputs">Taverna inputs. The required Taverna input port are selected from the corresponding columns. Ports
        	expecting a single value will only select from the first row, ports expecting multiple values will consume 
        	all rows for their corresponding columns. Any missing values are replaced with empty strings.</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="outputs">Taverna outputs. Each Taverna output port is represented as a column. Ports outputting a single
        	value will only have values in the first row. Note that columns might be padded with missing values as some Taverna ports
        	might have more output values than others.</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Workflow columns">Show expected input and output columns</view>
        <!--view index="1" name="name of second view">Description of second view...</view-->
    </views>
</knimeNode>
